<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Adithi R. Upadhya</title>
    <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Adithi R. Upadhya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adithirugis.netlify.app/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elephants of Karnataka - Atlas</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_06_01_atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_06_01_atlas/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe elephants in southern India are found in 7 states, predominantly in forested hilly tracks of the Western Ghats and its adjacent Eastern Ghats in the states of Karnataka, Kerala, Tamil Nadu and also as small numbers and population in Andhra Pradesh, Maharashtra and Goa. Of all the elephants in the country, Karnataka harbors the highest number of elephants. The typography, climate, vegetation and natural water resources of Karnataka shape this into a distinctive elephant region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Glacier Velocity</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2019_07_30_glacier_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2019_07_30_glacier_work/</guid>
      <description>AbstractGlacier movement is a crucial factor for assessing cryospheric climate change. Traditional methods of field surveys for studying glacier movement and velocity are often not possible owing to inaccessibility and harsh terrains. Furthermore, as it is not feasible to physically monitor and survey many glaciers around the globe, these traditional methods are limited in their global coverage. Remote sensing is an ideal tool to study such phenomena on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AssetConnect</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2018_04_18_assetconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2018_04_18_assetconnect/</guid>
      <description>AbstractGeospatial technology is a powerful tool for monitoring ground-based assets. The best way to visualize ground-based assets is by tracking asset conditions in space and time. Spatial information is one of the crucial requirements in decision making for ground-based assets. An effective asset management can improve the performance; strengthen the infrastructure and tackle current and future challenges. The asset management system focuses on reducing the maintenance while extending the lifetime of the asset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
