<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Adithi R. Upadhya</title>
    <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Adithi R. Upadhya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Deploying and Maintaining a Low-Cost PM2.5 Sensor Network</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2022_07_01_best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2022_07_01_best_practices/</guid>
      <description>AbstractStrategically placed sensors can monitor air pollution and provide a detailed picture of air quality and its variability within a region. Low-cost sensors (LCSs) that measure PM2.5 are becoming increasingly popular because of their low cost, ease of use, and portability. However, the portability and low cost come with trade-offs on data quality, reliability, and shelf life. The typical shelf life of LCSs is around a year to two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Assessment of Low-Cost PM2.5 Sensors</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2022_04_01_lcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2022_04_01_lcs/</guid>
      <description>AbstractAir pollution monitoring is an important aspect of air quality management. Strategically placed sensors can monitor air pollution and provide detailed information on air quality and its variability within a region. Low-cost sensors (LCSs) that measure PM2.5 (particulate matter with a size less than or equal to 2.5 microns) are becoming increasingly popular for monitoring air pollution because of their low cost and portability. However, the low cost and portability come with trade-offs on data quality, reliability, and shelf life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pollucheck</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_07_30_pollucheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_07_30_pollucheck/</guid>
      <description>Abstractpollucheck can handle real-time pollution and co-located meteorological data (if available) from the three most popular open-source air pollution databases: OpenAQ, AirNow, and Indian Central Pollution Control Board (CPCB) dashboard. While CPCB data are specific to Indian regulatory monitoring stations, OpenAQ hosts the global open-source pollution databases and AirNow hosts the global PM~2.5~ (mass concentration of particulate matter with an aerodynamic diameter less than or equal to 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elephants of Karnataka - Atlas</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_06_01_atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2021_06_01_atlas/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe elephants in southern India are found in 7 states, predominantly in forested hilly tracks of the Western Ghats and its adjacent Eastern Ghats in the states of Karnataka, Kerala, Tamil Nadu and also as small numbers and population in Andhra Pradesh, Maharashtra and Goa. Of all the elephants in the country, Karnataka harbors the highest number of elephants. The typography, climate, vegetation and natural water resources of Karnataka shape this into a distinctive elephant region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mmaqshiny</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2020_06_30_mmaqshiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2020_06_30_mmaqshiny/</guid>
      <description>Abstractmmaqshiny is for analysing, visualising and spatial plotting of high-resolution air quality data collected by specific devices installed on a moving platform. With the click of a button, the app generates: summary statistics, time series plots and spatial map of pollutant concentrations. This app reduces the time consumed for analysing each pollutant individually. It helps check the quality of the data at near real time (same day) and instantly visualise pollution hotspots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Glacier Velocity</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2019_07_30_glacier_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2019_07_30_glacier_work/</guid>
      <description>AbstractGlacier movement is a crucial factor for assessing cryospheric climate change. Traditional methods of field surveys for studying glacier movement and velocity are often not possible owing to inaccessibility and harsh terrains. Furthermore, as it is not feasible to physically monitor and survey many glaciers around the globe, these traditional methods are limited in their global coverage. Remote sensing is an ideal tool to study such phenomena on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AssetConnect</title>
      <link>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2018_04_18_assetconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adithirugis.netlify.app/project/2018_04_18_assetconnect/</guid>
      <description>AbstractGeospatial technology is a powerful tool for monitoring ground-based assets. The best way to visualize ground-based assets is by tracking asset conditions in space and time. Spatial information is one of the crucial requirements in decision making for ground-based assets. An effective asset management can improve the performance; strengthen the infrastructure and tackle current and future challenges. The asset management system focuses on reducing the maintenance while extending the lifetime of the asset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
